All right it's like ten forget started
I'd like to introduce myself my name is sam spencer I'm a program manager on the simultaneous
a microsoft so when I talk about today is the next evolution we've
added in...windows ten, for example, data binding so the big thing
that's driven kind requirements into the simultaneous for this release is we picked up some large
internal clients specifically office and windows shell but those teams one thing that really hard-core
...is performance...
Basically the office guys they can that hey if I
...a property through code versus sitting at three data binding
then that's orders of magnitude faster like okay,
let's see we fix that for you and then the...guys came along I said hey we need to kind of reduce the memory,
memory consumption...back kind of
...splash but with them so it's like okay that's a look at as well so what
we've come up with for this release is a new version
of data binding
calling compile binding and the big difference between this and what you've...
binding before is the heavy lifting which is kind of reflection work is now
done...build time rather than at runtime?
So, we classic binding ...create binding, binding objects binding path objects
...could reflection or other api is to figure out what are those types and,
...go kind of hooked together all
...what we do now is we do that at design-time we generate codes
...behind that means you can actually go inspect the code look at...it there's no magic going
on in data mining...also means we validation of the bindings so if you miss
type or the object models and public or whatever you get a compiler for it...build time.
So, at the end of the session what I...like what is compile binding you know-how do using
applications the pros and cons and have a brief understanding of what kind of going on the hood?
So, first we do is start off with the demo and.
this is a micro benchmark application of written ...this does...demonstrate differences between
...so I've got a series of user controls in here each of which
then has a stack panels with effectively grid
...forty border elements and each is boarder elements has background color a set with
a data binding in this case I'm using classic finding she that we boost up a bit?
Using classic...but I can also do it with x bind.
By doing this with a forty grid we're doing sixteen hundred elements it gives us something kind of measurable
to tracker performance so I flip back flip over to the runtime of this...see
the application action...new but nobody links we get a tyne...here this is kind of from
...to create use control till the frame is submitted to be rendered
...relatively...pretty good time but like what does it take to do
the tree operations get that page ready so no bindings we're talking about twenty-seven milliseconds.
One-time binding we're looking at eighty-one milliseconds...a little bit since we
...one seventy.
Sixty-eight each time I do it...different results subtext bind
...the seventy millisecond range comparing that with classic binding that's in the five
hundred millisecond range thanks...substantially faster in these kind of micro benchmarks
those are one-time bindings if I do one-way will see x
bind similarly about seventy milliseconds to give
...model when I hit the change color button what that does is changes change the data model and
changes all colors to random so that's taking can fifteen milliseconds.
Minding one-way...large
to create and change the color it takes more time.
I switch back to powerpoint what I've got here is a screenshot from
a tool we call wk windows performance analyzer...you guys familiar with
...we generally use internally to track performance into sample
base profiler so every millisecond it got a samples and that's what we're seeing for the top part of
this graph so this section is for classic binding this
...compile binding we can see I put in customer tw markers...
kind of the begin and end some compare that and you can see the cpu is basically pegged
twenty-five percent for the entire the entire time the reason it's twenty five percent of
hundred-percent...a for core machine and therefore...thread...picking one of...
Looking at the second part...generic events these are each w markers
...by example each one is represented as a little
diamond but if you get a whole bunch very close together that's where you end up with a bar.
So, what...showing is we do a whole bunch of element creation and then there's a lot of other
worked isn't can involving example tree we look at the same thing in compiled binding are
element creation is smaller and then the second section is substantially smaller?
So, I can do is...in the call stack to see what's kinda going on with this and we
see during the first part what we're doing is we're creating are binding objects.
That's why it takes more times
...elements and then the second part this whole gap...activity
really didn't seem to be going on that's where we get the data context changed notification and each those binding
expressions is now being parsed...understood
reflection what have you age-wise taking kind of so much longer.
So,...buying what we've done is move that work to compile-time rather than runtime.
So, that was a cpu from a memory
...compile binding because we don't have the binding object is also substantially
small so we can see here is example no bindings one-time with x
...a little bit higher classic binding substantially higher
explain one-way is a little bit higher than the one-time
...listener objects and then finding one-way is substantially larger that again.
So, this was a micro benchmark kind of
accentuate the differences between binding but
...context of real applications start recently moved to
exponent they...overall reduction in a heap ten percent
...percent if you just look at memory district attributable those
...that's quite a good...quite good reduction in memory just by...binding expressions.
The people lap on the phone they just switched over.
...csharp their startup is down eleven percent
...thirty-two heap is down twenty one percent just by changing to expand.
So, some good performance kind of...in the technology.
So, how do I use compile binding well the simplest view is you take the
school binding expression and replace it with x columbine?
But,...a bit more to it than that we look to see could we convert this technology and
use it put that kind of place...the bindings...is the traditional bindings used
...use the same expression problems we couldn't do it will while being
...compatible and we need extra typing information isn't available to
...traditional binding so with classic binding it
turns use data context or a source property set on the binding object.
Both of those are object type so we don't have the type information we need to go
decode generation so for ex bind do code generation we need that type
information so strongly typed so for bindings inside a page or
user control we use that pager user control itself as the context for the bindings?
The other big changes made is because we want to pay for playful performance
change the default...the binding from being one way to one-time you
still use one-way just need to be explicit opt into the to work is going to go on for that.
Let's take a look at what it takes to use text bind in my in your...
Should switch...
So, what I've got here is?
A very simple application I've got a page with text blocking it and
...behind I've got to fields
...code data and a model field ...model.
Not model has a bunch of different properties over here it's the same...using the
...sample.
So, to actually use x bind what I can do is just do.
X combined.
If I run it that's now going to find that data field and
...combine to that also means you combine to fields.
Very simple kind of instance data mining we support all
the same expression types pretty much you can do and classic binding so I could do.
If I do string proper line pc and now build.
What I'm actually getting is a compiler here saying
...confines string pepperdine pc that's because I
misspell the w so capitalized again build?
So, that's an instance of the...validation we do is...compilers note
...that...time rather than at runtime.
Chance of you running into problems runtime now significantly less.
...here is a demo app this is an early drop off
demolition sdk those got published today about to pm
so you go download it will be black is grossly different menu but all the rest of is exactly the same.
So, what I've got in here is a set of different bindings so one-time binding pretty obvious
we'll read the field...fields properties dependency properties he said
one-time we don't do any change detection kind of works pretty much...
One-way binding I can still trying to one-way binding
...field or a property that doesn't have I and pc on
...class and in those cases were not going to get the changes will get the changes if you
implement identify property changed or ...property so...have here is
...fields as I update the data model my ui updates respectively.
We also support index path bindings so this if you want to bind to a particular
member of a collection it's not so much for list scenarios but like hey I
...find that's the first customer or those kind of scenarios then I can use.
Square brackets and integer to index into that particular collection.
...a recent values binding to.
Textbooks little bit boring combine just about any control in a
...anyway so, what I have here is an to a bindings these
...to the model as I just this slider
it will adjust the other one that's bound to the same model property similarly for this guy
...also got like other elements down here the bound to the same thing
...bindings pretty much the same syntax
...before so I have a toggle switch here it's...property and then I'm
binding the visibility ...this property to that so if I go to?
...basic tests sorry...moi.
So, we can look at this I have a toggle switch...bound
...boolean property with change educational model you don't...mpc whatever is just kind of
...purposes name that way so each binding the visibility same
...kind of do before same problem that the model
is boolean property visibility is em type how do I get
...to in them so you need to converter so we support exactly the same converters using I
value converter...classic binding if you're familiar with...data binding...nothing here that's kind of really
new and revolutionary just a different squiggles just a different pining expression the beginning.
Showing some other stuff in this markup.
If I want to binds to
another element in my page with classic binding you would
...and binding and specify the particular element length.
Compile binding because we using the page or can
use control has a data context if you name
and element as a field generated in there you could bind directly to element...field so in this case I
combine...one just because that's actually a great on that's named it gets field
...my page...buying directly to it so here's an example using index...property?
I've got a local textbooks I bind a bunch of other things to that so
for instance this expression...csharp doesn't work with cplus-plus could
...links isn't a property there but in this case when it
My hello world text you'll see the counter down...change along with it.
And, how that's working is that's bound to text property of
that local textbooks in using the link property?
And, because the text is a
...property that...change notification ...causes to evaluate the rest expression as well.
So, it's kind of simple bindings we can also buying things like a...column attach properties we
...to attach properties so in this case this is actually
...a grid with ten columns defined and as I just
...sliders adjusting the ...for
those elements this image has...to transform on it so,
I combinedproperties with inside the...the rent...
...translate a rotating translate
...to update values you'll see that moves...that moves.
We also do target null value and fullback value target
...value is when the leaf node of...binding expression is null so in this case
if first name was null than and specified a target no value that
would get used in place for the binding fullback value is used in other parts of the binding
...return null were little bit more sensitive to errors
and classic binding you'll...get exception
you can breakthroughs see the code step through and figure out what happens were little bit more.
Debug...I should say is probably...putting.
All right I think that's something I wanted to show there.
So, considerations for data binding using x bind.
Data conversion.
Will implicitly converts to and from string so, if you're binding to binding a text
block ...by not to ensure failed automatic cool to string for you?
And, the other direction we have...and api to use assemble parsers logic
...to objects...target...value fullback value
and using those on say a background property which needs to be a brush.
Then on...specify...but how do I do that...string the parser already supports
that that's how I can say my background is read so I can simply use read in the value here for x
buying fullback value...use that same...logic to translate that into solid color brush
for sagan you pound faa...whatever.
The case where you converters is when you can't do...directing code so we can do
widening conversions automatically or implicitly so you're binding and integer
to a value on the slider which is double that
...conversion...happens automatically...versa doesn't if
you want to use converter then you implement I value converter just as you would in classifying today.
For one-way and two-way bindings.
We listens change notifications if it's a property
in supports identify poppy change search parent class implements that.
Or if it's dependency property...one of the piece of infrastructure
...added in windows ten is a new api that you can register on object
...prepare for change certifications on any dependency property
...not just limited to once you define...go register for the
textbook text whatever that basically how we...due to a binding as well and,
if you're doing a index paths minding which binding into the collection
using square brackets will look for identify collection changed
...or items...vector.
So, if there's...collection changeswe'll go and redo the bindings that point.
Two-way binding the limitation there is that the property only you why I never was
...source of the target as long as for
confused that binding but he why property needs depend needs to be a dp
depends property we don't listen for events we just use the same depends property
change replication mechanism hook this up the one exception that we special case
...is the text property on textbooks in which case to keep the case kinda
same kind behaviors before we now listen to lost focus wait for that to occur before
...text property other than that it's very similar to classic binding.
another place words really common to do data binding is inside data template.
With pages and use controls we can use the type of the page...control as a basis
for our bindings for data template we need to know what type of item is data this
...going to be used with so what we've done is we've added a new attribute x
...data type on the...the template you can specify that data type
using the stand kind of xml name space decode name space mapping so in this case.
It's model maps to...maximal...map
...of...model ...just use I employee here it doesn't have to be
...interface component a type uone.
So, employees have a name so I can just now
...the name property in here and that's bound to the name of the employee.
It's pretty common with data templates to want to put them inside
...resource dictionary so I can be used in multiple places
in your application if you do that we need to have a place to go
stick the code jan for that data template.
So, this maxus that you need to do if you're using
the x bind inside of a data template inside
...resource dictionary first change is you need to give it a class in this case...my templates.
Just by adding excludes definition to.
Encode you need to create a
...class for that and then in the constructor that class
...into initialized component if you forget to do this ...happen is...runtime is not
...actually loaded the resource
...been one of quite a while trying to figure why is my part
my example blowing up at initialize component every time is because you haven't necessarily
...resources...speaking from experience of finding those problems.
Final thing is we need to have that
...cold so rather than loading the resource dictionary with a
source.
The filename I need to specify
...class so in this case my templates.
That...course...get called that
...initialize component...load resources and dual hookup force.
So, flipping back let's take a look at some examples.
Of data templates.
So, what have in this case is a series of different
list scenarios so I've got a list
...with a data temple inline the only thing I need to change
...classic binding is adding the x data type
...work-up my slide demo from and I combine to name property?
For...a bit yes...better.
If I want to do a data template inline I can.
...to add the data type there I can also refer to
...and that's used in here.
Diverge...will static resources I would normally
...resource I can also do it to...resources defined a template file
...my template example looks almost exactly the same as always just have now
got x class statement and now using explained in here.
My...behind for it all I have is that partial class definition calling into initialized component.
Listen this...templates kind of all those list views hooked together you'd expect
...collection changes the bindings links will update.
One of the thing to dimension I'll show you actually encode.
Data templates are not just used in list scenarios you can also
use them as a content template so in this case I've got a button and I
specify that content template to be the same a template those using...list...
And, now forts content I have an index
...binding into the employees collection so that is yielding
and I employee and.
That's being used as the content template for the control.
So, far we've talked about is functionality kinds is brings us up to parity between
x...what I can do in classic binding.
But, we...to go further than that so the first thing I won't talk about
is x face.
So, if you developing applications for a tablet or something kind of slow like this guy
just turned off...have to...again.
Sure, the second then for a list scenarios what we have what we do is we
...window over a much larger surface so when you
...with touch we moving that surface that happens kind of lower-level the
...manipulative...the application is responsible for is rendering items on
that surface...of...like a conveyor belt and window is going to put the items on that
...fast enough that when it comes past window indivisible everything is there in the
right place however if your machine is kind of slow than as we recycle elements
and taken from one-off kind of from the and that's no longer used on to the end is used
we'll do that fast enough to keep up with the speex depending.
On the machines we can't necessarily do that.
So, in windows three-point-one we introduced a feature called the can-you container
content changing event this is an event on list view you get called back for each
item allows you to progressively...the...item templates.
Really powerful feature...solves use a problem...do it you have to write code
...code...concludes the use of data binding.
So, what we do what we've done with x bind and...new feature of x
phase this allows us to do it declarative lee rather than implicitly through code?
So,...here is.
...template.
Couple textbooks and textbooks,
textbooks and it is a small example ability demo shown...and
...is prioritize what I show in order so I want to display
name to all we show so I'm not given...face of left that
is implicit ...it phase zero...zero automatically get bound automatically
shown but showing the date is less important impending fast
...filename is what really what I care about so I can delay that...what I've done is
I've specified when additional attribute...convene phase one.
What that means is that field or that control will be hidden until the
phase comes into play...we updated we hide it so
...we're recycling elements we don't have stale data shown interview...
It's probably best illustrated when example.
You switch to the calmer.
...to login again.
So, this will be is a to...on core to is a betrayal atom device
optimize...battery life rather than cpu performance so what I have here
is running yes.
We...what I have here is a list view with a bunch of pictures
of downloaded...
Each the item has a couple different textbooks in there and the image
...using classic bindings of append fast.
...see is we quite quickly end up in a situation where can't keep up and we kind of end up in white?
Not the best user experience.
We can change that using x bind.
A little bit little bit betterwould say well hang on to make
...so much faster isn't going to solve all
...all...hunger will piece it makes the binding part faster but it doesn't make the setting a
...faster and that's the part is actually really slow here you would think setting
...is actually pretty easy once you start having all international everything else and text is a lot more work
...is quite slow so what I can do is switch over to x
buying the next phase if I pan in this example again what you'll see is when
I go-fast we end up just showing the first-line of the item?
Which is its title and then if we have time we'll go...the other pieces so
...progressively come in...have...one item their...sometimes
...two-a-three...image is the final piece of that puzzle so that's
although and...device you can find the same kind of thing on phones?
...like...so x phase is
what allows me to delay progressively incrementally...the item template.
Some guidance for this technically there is no limit on how many faces you could use
but I recommend keeping it to handful if you do more than that it's
...good generally spend more work figuring out the phases and actually doing work.
We still...ccc event so if you want you can hook
...up as well into your logic in addition to the binding work.
And, the ccc...hooked up will fired of first for each phase so you get called for
...zero then phase one the phrase to...
The phase numbers in use with...can't phase don't need to be
continuous I could have won ten thousand but, again, keep it...handful but,
it can it doesn't mean that you can leave adapt one or two if you need to ccc
working between for instance between a particular phases.
In terms of how many faces you need for your
app that's really going to come down to your app what you're kind
...binding to pixel density to kind of control amount...work
...to...those different pieces so really what...need to do is try it get your
hands-on a slow device the sixty...a great for that kind of thing and try it
...profile it used to...use
...profiling capabilities visual studio to figure out what's actually taking time and
optimize that.
The other big feature we've added for x combines
which is new is the ability to bind events...why we haven't done this before.
Traditionally with events if I have a button here with...method...employee needs to
be method on my code behind...we can now do with x combined is instead
...complex combined and
then a binding expression and now bind to wherever that expression the needs to.
So, whatever method that is inside model will if it doesn't need to have any parameters
if we'll get a parameter will bind parameters functions or it needs to match the
...signature this cases button click so it's sender and routed
Alternative you can also use a signature that has base types of the event
we can call that directly so in this case of may...used object rather
...event...you can use whatever base or interface classes you need.
A couple, couple limitations here we don't support overloaded methods try to figure out
from...of admit methods which is the right one for event we say pay which can look for poke
...one version of poker.
I can do this all events not just click.
And, if you're...mgm developer it can replace some of the instances
the uses of I command and event command behavior.
I can use on any event...to use and
event command the one thing to consider is if you're using I command buttons.
That will look at the can execute decide whether to enable
...button you can just do...as a separate binding instead if you
need that we also don't have a command parameter but we passing the object you can use
...tag of other touch properties on there if you need data for that particular item
So, taking a quick the switch over to my demo for this.
So,...my event bindings what I have here is actually it's
...the code first.
What I have is a
...kind of a click with regular arguments no arguments base
arguments these are just methods on my page it's not kind-of so exciting that way?
But, I can...buying to them the using x bind as I expect
not limited to methods on my page I combine to any
...model properties I want in this case index path into a collection.
What is becomes particularly interesting useful is in
...scenarios so in this case I have my data template for employee and,
my...a button here...going to call...this defined on
...employee so if I run this guy?
...binding what we'll see is
...set of different employees some are individual contributors and some
...I think ryan is an individual...says he's been poked
...implementation on employee was have classes that are manager also
and implements employee so in this case quentin is
...manager...employees of quentin rather than just quentin itself so that's two different
...methods depending on which item and binding to in the collection id
...because I was trying to figure out what
...the words to use but they all kind of ended up being a hr violations or problem?
X...code generation the initialization...bindings is going to be different from
...classic...what we've done is we've created a new event called loading was already
loaded...event but loaded occurs after the initial measure and
arrange passes occurred loading occurs before that and we use
...kind of lost best point to go and in
update a bindings without having to go redo the measurement
would occur if I did afterwards again so implicitly we'll call bindings initialize as part of
loading event if you have your own data and you you-can call initialize yourself initialize
is guarded...call...as many times you want it...you actually do the work once?
Now if I'm making asynchronous
calls the file system or pulling down data from the web icon guarantees I'm going to
get a data in time before that loading event occurs so instead what I can do is I can use a method off
the bindings object bindings property that we...to your code that has a method that has the
initialize update and stop tracking if I call update that will update
...bindings including one-time bindings so after the
...data you can call update and that will refresh...bindings for that particular scope.
If you if for some unknown reason you're doing a whole bunch of work you could change a whole bunch of
properties and you don't want the two-way the one-time.
One way and two-way bindings to...that point you kind of want to delay the binding work you
can call stop tracking on the bindings object that will pours...tracking.
...when you're ready
...bindings update again and that will force...forcefully updates all bindings and page.
Another thing to consider is one-way binding is more expensive than one-time but we have to
create listener objects and hook up to line...
If you-know-who say...you could use...displays all the stuff for an employee if, you know,
the data is going to change the employee then what you could do is do one-time bindings
all throughout that and if the data has changed...bindings...that point...all
...scripting...so sometimes that can be actually more efficient than
having a whole bunch of change listeners listening and poking around and every time
...past changes you can actually...update in one particular place similarly for lists?
If I if I was doing...with the files and point of the file system.
File system doesn't change very much...unlikely that the
...will changes more likely if something happens...going to deleted I'm going
...we need to replace more than one binding on that if I...buying if I doone-way binding
...listening to every property...every item there that's an awful lot of change list is going on
something is going to happen very frequently the other thing you could consider there is
rather firing granular changes for individual properties fire change for the item
as a whole using identify collection changed and then refresh
that will enforce refresher the entire object.
Not all the binding paths need to support change notifications survivor one-time but
...one-way binding for every node in that we will look to see
whether to dependency property or implements
identify property changed it does great will register if we don't it
doesn't matter as long as one part does and that's where that's what you care about the listening.
Final one is a little bit kind of complicates explain.
We have the binding scopes that's like a page use control data template.
As...processing this...we do is we build-up a graph of
all binding expressions and we process those as a whole so if I
in this case I have two control if I to controls one bound to first in property one down to lasting
property and both share along complex finding path then for the model
the manager prop the reports oc...index into that those are shared and common
between them soldier generate one function for each of those steps and then it's only with
things divergent where you actually get extra code generated a pretty
efficient sharing the binding expressions between multiple bindings within that same scope.
So, let's have a look at what we're doing under the hood ...
If I go back and I taint change this just to be say hello world.
And, I build this guy.
We now do is drill into the code that's generated
for that so we generate to files a gps energy to
icy doi happens in the first phase of compilation that's generally different teller sense if
you're apt compile the geo cs we can build the second phase of
the compilation and that relies on being able...data that you creating the first
...public data from the first phase and reflector so in this case it looks very similar
...did before one change we've made for windows ten is we used to use just
...connect method for hooking up events we now use it for hooking up names so previously we used
...inside of initialize component will be fine names
...controls with change that to using a connect and connection id because find name
volta tree walk that's expensive example it's much faster
have the runtime call back into the code and say hey here's a textbook...and slider here's whatever.
So, that's kind of what's going on in the most basic case now if I change this
to being x combined.
I just named I just change name sorry.
Yeah, no, I hate typing onstage during demos.
Thank you.
Yes.
We should now see when I expand this guy...main page
...quite a bit more stuff so we've now got a property in your
page that's fine ...to do-do-do-do bindings.
That's bindings object you-can call initialize everything else off
...type of this interface we then generate a class here the
implements the interface this is where all the logic for...
occurs so in this class what we'll see is here's our initialize
...update are stop tracking methods we have a field for each control within a bank buying
...and then we have a series of update methods so for each.
Binding path node in that binding scope will great create and update method so
...underscores for the...and all I used was data in this case so it
...an update data method that intern
...into some static set of functions we have to go and update the text property that
So, that's just for kind-of hell the simple data case if I make this
more complex binding expressions so.
We say make this model.
...explicit.
If...what we should see is that
the update data message goes away instead we now have an update model method and that intern
...into update model the string...pc.
So, it's walking is binding paths generating appropriate,
appropriate methods and you can actually go step into this code separate points as you need to.
If I copy this.
And, remove the name.
Rebuild.
What...see is we should see no additional functions because we've got to bindings using that same
method so, that same path but now we havethat final node that's
calling into to setters one for object two-one for object three there's...textbooks?
If I change this guide to say...
...instead.
Which now see over here?
As we still have a model we the model method now calls into
two children one for the string property one for the entity property.
So, kind of this pattern is what we do to build-up the logic for...bindings if I
change this from one-time to one-way what we're now going to do is
look to see page that classes support identify property changed it does I've
got one binding the is dependent on that let-me generate some code for that.
What...now see is we've got additional objects around and we've
gotten additional class this is the bindings tracking object?
And, this
...has a property change methods what we've done here who created a separate
class to listen to the event handlers and the reason for that is because the can-we
...event handle patten in the
example when you handle one of those events were handing over is an object and
...method and several keepsthe model will keep the object alive
so rather than having the object be something that's tied to the...in keep
...or alive we've done what we've done is create a small little objects that can listen to
those change invocations and that then has a week reference
backer to a binding object so we do get a leak...just leaking a very small
object that...that's just the kind of tracking rather than leaking all...so
in this guy we have a property change method that's doing a pretty standards kind of
...pc lookup if it's empty it'll update that property otherwise it'll go to switch
on which property name is used...things respectively it also has
an update childless method and this is what will actually go...that change detection so
...of really rocket science in the code...generating here is taking
a binding expressions parsing them spitting out of a bunch of code?
The only thing we really needed from the framework was
depends property changed capability that we using here you can use
...in theory you could go if you're masochist you could
...all this code by hand there's nothing framework special specific that we're doing here but,
it's much easier to have something go and generate that particularly when you end up with long
binding expressions we need to listen to changes on every single node
as that goes on.
there are some differences between compile binding and classic finding we don't support relative
source equal self or element name equivalence next bind is just to give those
guys name the total creative field you can buy into that field oppressed everything works.
We don't support
...relative source is template parent for...expressions.
Are generally in a control template you want use a template binding
anyway the documentation says a template binding and classic binding with
...relative source...of the same utilize the not?
Classic...a lot more expensive than template binding
...use template binding the cases where you need to useother binding
their use classic binding unique cases
...if you need converter or you need to binding to be other than one-way.
Finally with classic binding it relies on
...source property or data
context to be set compile binding we need that type information that's not available there.
You content dynamically...that point options are user kind of...path to get the data
quite efficient dealing with those alternative just add another
...your page...into that we combine to fields...you need to.
...would not deprecated classic binding it's still there we need
it there are cases that we can't handle in compile
bindingclassifying is much better for...typing is one.
I thought the name description architect but apparently this is a common phrase it comes
...basis of it walks like a dot...like a duck taste like duck...treated as a doug.
So, what that means for classic finding is kind of person object and the
...object to completely independent objects
...based class or interface...between them
...have an each property as far as classic bindings concerned runtime...page of an age
...page community so it can work with those with x bind we need to know what
type that is now we do allow you to use
...expression to specify data type?
But, as can be a lot of work and isn't necessarily appropriate...scenarios?
Which case continues classic binding pictionary graphs similarly if I
...blob of...download...of...object whatever?
We don't know from that if I...serialized
...classes what the types are expo a classic binding works better if you
...kind of dot into those type of objects.
Finally we don't support programmatic binding creation everything has to be the compile-time.
That you can still do with classic binding one
of the primary case though I've seen in our internal apps...actually using
...binding is primarily to get kind of notifications of dependency properties
so now we have an easier way of doing that so if that's what you're trying to do just register for
...the change all that depends property rousing creating a binding together.
Yes, sorry I didn't.
Yes.
...pull up an example.
...can switch back over here.
...others, others other...
...a casing...
...here's...example so,
...this case and binding to the background property on the page the background that type the
properties of type brush or reviews...I think ...really want to get
too is the color of a solid color brush if I just left that...actually remove this.
...do live events?
What I should get from that case is a compiler because it'll say?
Come on.
Yes, invalid binding...it can't find color off the brush.
If I go back in here.
We do is use
...attach property syntax cassette to solid color brush and say hey I want to access
the color property of this feature is actually available in classic binding.
We found it...it's vaguely documented.
It is mentioned kind of in...piece you can do...you can do this retype properties own
...like udp so,...is there is
...needed in classifying because invariably.
Unless the objects implementing separate interfaces and the exposing the functionality the interface
you can normally find the property there but with x buying we need that kind of capability so you can
...there ...it that way.
So, that's kind of the functionality we've got in this release of x
bind and sample it's a new feature this time we...coming hot I'm sure when you try
you'll find bugs if so please tell us ...fix them but,...this further that we
want to go ...we've implemented so far so I'm not giving any promises but if you see
joe segmental tim...given...kick and say hey can you do this feature please seems...much more...
weight played on customer request internal of things we're thinking about in future ability to
buying to a function so every don't like converters they're...web doing it...
buying to a function instead and specify the function parameters the binding paths ...of
...prototypes of it I think I think that one will end up doing but it can also solve
the multiplying...solution as well because I can now buying to multiple expressions at the same time together is
...function.
Other things we think amount so for data templates we kind of create this code behind for
a class for it but it's not really truly
combine class that you as a developer can go play with your data templates so, we're looking at
been thinking at there is how do I enable you to specify your own class of
...data template and have your own logic ties together with function binding...functions in
their and users with inside that the binding...data template and also how could I then scope
and access...stuff from...data object from
my class or larger scope we don't have a solution for find ancestor?
...so far I think that would solve the most
common need the most common cases for it something that we're thinking about looking at.
Phasing right now is only support in data templates
...make sense there but if you step back a bit and say hey we could I enable
this start-up as well...how do we pass that...down the tree so if
we're going to use control inside...data template right now that use control...have one phase but we don't
unable kind of sub phases with inside that...use control to be defined
...of bubble up and then if I do some phases...make that work with the rest of kind of the phasing
...so some work to do that to think about it but,...that's one of the other features
we're looking at for expand finally can we have a better solution for unknown object graphs like
jason or xml data.
So, wrapping up we introduced a new form
...binding in windows ten compile binding.
Generally replaces most the functionality classic running and is faster and
uses less memory if you find bugs please a or got feedback
...the feedback...or not talk to us here?
In terms of extra sessions there's another one today five p.
And, then on friday really interesting is a talk by.
Andrew inco from the office team on their uses animal in office so the
modern offices actually built on top...they...make sure infrastructure work
the during a talk on...of how they've used...xhtml.
Together with office the demo apple they're showing that's just early drop all of the
demo...sdk...go online...to pm today so-if you
...you want to go play with phasing whatever download the sample.
And, play with your much.
I should say fill out evaluation form it's really good for us it's really
good for the session planners thank you.